Countries collection, 1540-2006 (bulk 1920-1970)
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Countries collection
1540-2006
1920-1970
MS 445
64 boxes (32 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
The Countries collection is comprised predominantly of printed materials, with some photographs and manuscript materials. It focuses on the status of women, women's organizations, and feminist movements in over 140 countries. Related topics include sex roles; political rights; educational opportunities for women; biographical information on such notable individuals as Madame Chiang Kai-Shek, Indira Gandhi, Eva Peron, and Joan of Arc; plus information on women's organizations and conferences. Countries more prominently represented include Canada, China, England, France, Germany, India, Japan and the United States.
The Countries Collection is comprised predominantly of printed materials such as reports, articles, newspaper clippings, biographical sketches, pamphlets, books, newsletters and periodicals, as well as some photographs, letters, and manuscript materials. The collection focuses on the status of women and feminist movements in over 140 countries. Related topics include sex roles, political rights, educational opportunities for women, and biographical information on such notable individuals as Madame Chiang Kai-Shek, Indira Gandhi, Eva Peron, and Joan of Arc. There is also information on women's organizations and conferences in various countries. The collection dates from 1540 to 2006 with the bulk of the material dating from circa 1920 to 1980. Countries more prominently represented include Canada, France, Germany, India, Japan and the United States.
Some unique materials include letters (in German) from a young Jewish women telling of deplorable conditions in Germany in the 1920s; sixteenth century marriage treaties written in old French; nineteenth century photographs of North American Indians (under Regions); a 1937 travel log of a woman in South Africa; a typescript for an Encyclopedia of Woman's History in Japan compiled by Baroness Ishimoto in the 1930s; and pamphlets on women's rights from various countries from the nineteenth and early twentieth century.
The materials are arranged alphabetically by country from Aden to Zimbabawe. There is a separate section at the end called World Regions which includes materials on Africa, Asia, and Latin America, etc. Where the scope of the materials warranted further arrangement, materials are usually arranged in the following categories: Biographical material, Clippings, Conferences and reports, General, Publications, and Women's Organizations. The U.S. section includes materials about women in U.S. history arranged by period including the Colonial period, the Civil War, and the 20th century, followed by files on U.S. regions and individual states.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The collection is open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection.
History of the Collection
Materials in this subject collection were either purchased or given to the Sophia Smith Collection by various donors. Periodic additions are expected.
Finding aid revised by Jessica Lawson (intern), 2004. It was revised in 2016 by Maida Goodwin.
Search Terms
Feminism--History--Sources; Women--History--Sources; Women's rights--History--Sources; Women--International cooperation--History--Sources; Women--Africa--History--20th century--Sources; Women--Asia--History--Sources; Women--United States--History--Sources; Women--India--History--Sources; Women--Japan--History--Sources; Women--Middle East--History--Sources; Indians of North America--History--19th century
- Aden [see Yemen] (Box 1)
- Afghanistan
  - Clippings, 1929-77 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Women's organizations
    - General (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Afghan Women's Welfare Society, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Revolutionary Association of the Women of Afghanistan (RAWA), 2000-01 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Albania, 1967-71 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Algeria
  - Clippings, 1957-70 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Biographical materials: Khemisti, Mohammed, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Publications: Femmes Nouvelles, Mar 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Andorra, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Angola, 1956-63 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Argentina
  - Biographical materials
    - General, 1929-58 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Peron, Eva, 1945-56 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Interviews with prominent Argentinian women, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1923-71, undated (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Conferences and reports
    - General, 1944, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Problema de la Coordinación de Organizaciones Voluntarias, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 6a)
    - Seminario Nacional Participacion de la Mujer en la Vida Publica, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Women in Argentina, circa 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8-10)
  - Publications: Five Months in the Argentine From a Woman's Point of View, 1918 to 1919 by Katherine S. Dreier, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Women's Organizations
    - General, 1955-65, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Asociacion Cristiana Feminina de Cordoba (YWCA), 1968-69 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Asociación Femenina de Acción Rural (AFAR), 1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Centro Femenino de Cultua Civica, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Consejo Argentino de Mujeres Israelites, 1961-68 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Departamento de la Mujer, 1967-68 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Intercambio Civico Social Feminino, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Australia
  - Clippings, 1893-1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Biographical materials (Box 3)
    - Henry, Alice: biographical materials, 1935-38 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Woods, Mary Tenison, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Publications
    - Pamphlets, 1937-58, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - The Country Woman of Western Australia, 1966-68 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - The Women's College Within the University of Sydney, Vol. 11892-1939, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Women's Organizations
    - Australian National Council of Women, 1968-69 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Australian Federation of Women Voters, 1948-58, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Australian Woman's Charter, 1943-49 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Women's Agricultural Bureau of South Australia, 1962-66 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1947-76 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Austria
  - Biographical materials
    - General, 1924-45 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Beth, Eleanor, 1923-38, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Hainisch, Marianne, 1909-29 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1920-63 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Publications, 1902-c.a. 1963 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Women's organizations, 1956-67, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Bahrain, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Bangladesh, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Basutoland [see also Lesotho]
  - Basutoland Homemakers Association, 1960-65 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Save the Children Fund, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Belgium
  - Biographical materials, 1924-63 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets, 1945-65, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Publications, 1896-1955 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Women's organizations, 1958-63 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Bermuda, 1929-31 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Bolivia
  - Biographical materials, 1926-67, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1945-52 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets, 1964-68 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Botswana, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Brazil
  - Biographical materials, 1924-72 (Box 5, Folder 5-8)
  - Clippings, 1924-72 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
  - Women's organizations
    - Brasil-Estados Unidos Movimento de Desenvolvimento e Organização de Comunidade (BEMDOC), 1966 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Centro de Proteção À Infância e Maternidade (CEPIM), 1964 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Movimento Brasiliero de Correspondêcia, 1956-68, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Federação de Ob ras Sociais (FOS), 1963-65 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Instituto Brasil-Estados Unidos de Vitoria, 1967-68, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Legião Brasileira de Assistência, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Organizacâo das Voluntárias, 1965-67 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Reports
    - "Brazilian Women Leaders in Civic Affairs," Conference, Washington, DC, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Family Life in Recife, Institute of Current World Affairs, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Status of women in Brazil, 1944-56 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Brazilian government reports, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Women's organizations
    - General, 1964, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Ação Democrática Feminina Gaúcha, 1965-69 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Associação Brasileira de Mulheres Universitárias, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Associação Cristã Feminina, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Associção de Pais e Amigos dos Excepcionais ded São Paulo (APAE), 1967, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Campanha da Mulher pela Democracia (CAMDE), 1964 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Cruzada da Mulher Democrata, 1965, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Federação Brasileira Pelo Progresso Feminino, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Liga das Senhoras Catolicas, 1962-64, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Liga Feminina Israleita do Brasil, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Movimento de Arregimentação Feminina, 1954-59, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - União Civica Feminina, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Rio de Janiero and São Paulo women's clubs bulletins, 1956, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Bulgaria
  - Biographical materials
    - Demchevsky, Margaret, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Karavelova, Ekaterina, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Clippings, 1915-33 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Publications: The Bulgarian Woman, Nov 1969, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Women's organizations, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Burma
  - Clippings, 1955-59, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Publications: "Burma" by Ma Mya Sein, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Women's organizations
    - General, 1955-58, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Burmese Women's League, 1954-55 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Girl Guides Association, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - National Council of Women of Burma, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Burundi, 1963-64 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Cambodia, 1959-64 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Cameroon, 1963-66 [see also Nigeria] (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Canada
  - Biographical materials
    - Benerman, Jean MacKay, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Belleville, Catherine Gauchet de, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Bullion, Angelique Faure de, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Carr, Emily, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Fairclough, Ellen, 1957-59 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Frémont, Thais Lacoste, 1929-61 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Gameliu, Mère (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Hind, E. Cora, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Hodges, Nancy, 1949-50 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Lacoste, Sir Alexandre (father of Thais Frémont), 1923-54 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - McCluny, Nellie, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - MacPhail, Agnes, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Mance, Jeanne, 1917-30 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Meagher, Margaret, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Rollet, Marie, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Saint-Jean, Idola, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Smith, Mary Ellen Spear, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Watt, Mand, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 1922-80 (Box 6, Folder 21-23)
  - Conferences and reports
    - Submission to the Royal Commission on the Status of Women by Association of United Ukranian Canadians, Mar 1968 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - L'Orientation des Filles en Milieu Scolaire, Conseil du Statut de la Femme, Nov 1977 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - General, 1981-91, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Photographs: Quebec "habitants," undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Publications
    - General
      - 1948-69 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - 1970-78 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Communiqu'elles, Jan 1970 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Dans le Melee, un numéro special sur la condition feminine, 8 Mar 1980 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - La Revue des Fermières, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Social Welfare Women's Number, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Women's Organizations
    - General, 1956-77 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Fédération des Femmes Canadiennes-Françaises. 1931-36, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - National Council of Women of Canada, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Women's Bureau, Department of Labour
      - Bulletin, 1962-65 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Directory of National Women's Organizations, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Reports, 1966-69 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Caroline Islands, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Ceylon [see also Sri Lanka]
  - Biographical materials
    - General, 1959-61 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Bandaranaike, Sirimavo, 1960-77 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1957-68 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Conferences and reports: All Ceylon Women's Conference, 1951-68 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Publications, 1958-60 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Women's organizations
    - General, 1962, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Ceylon Housewives Association, 1958-59 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Ceylon Women's Lawyers Association (CWLA), 1968\\ (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Girl Guides Association, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - YWCA of Ceylon, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Chile
  - Biographical materials
    - General, 1929-55 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - Allende, Hortensia Bussi de, 1971, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Figueroa, Ana, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Godoy Alcayaga, Lucilia (Gabriela Mistral, pseud.), 1926-57 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Figueroa, Ana, 1951-54 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Labarca, Amanda, 1946-48 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1920-72 (Box 8, Folder 7-9)
  - General, 1944-74 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- China
  - Biographical materials
    - Yu-Fang Chang, 1939-40 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Soumay Cheng, 1927-29 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Chiang Ching, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Li Dze-Djeu, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - W. A. S. Goh, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Mme. Sun Yat-Sen, 1927-32 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Mme. Chiang Kai-Shek, 1925-66 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, 1926-72 (Box 8, Folder 18-21)
  - General, 1912-72 (Box 8, Folder 22-24)
  - Chinese rice paintings and post cards, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Publications
    - General, 1949-67, undated (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - "Free China" (Taiwan Area, in Chinese), 1952-56 (Box 9, Folder 3-6)
  - Women's Organizations
    - General, 1939-62 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - All-China Women's Democratic Federation (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Chinese Women's Anti-Aggression League (CWAAL) (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Chinese Women's Club (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Women's Association for the Study of Asian Problems (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Women's Committee of the United Nations Association of the Republic of China, 1960-61 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Y.W.C.A. of China, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Columbia
  - Biographical materials: Mejia, Eladia, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1944-70, undated (Box 10, Folder 2-6)
  - General (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Publications
    - Ayudemos: Boletin Informativo al Servicio del Voluntariado Hospitalario Colombiano, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Informe Femenino: Boletin del Consejo Nacional de Mujeres, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Women's organizations
    - General, 1956, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Asociacion Christina Femenina (YWCA), 1966-68 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Unidad Femenina Nacional Programa Civico, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Union de Ciudadanas de Colombia, 1959-66, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Congo, Democratic Republic of (formerly Zaire; Belgian Congo)
  - Clippings, 1930, 1963, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - General, 1963-65, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Publications
    - Action Feminine, Movement Familial Chrétien: pamphlets (in French), 1964-66 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Congo Cobwebs, 1953-54 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Congo Crosses: A Study of Congo Womanhood by Julia Lake Kellersberger, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Eva Revue de la Femme Moderne (in French), 1961 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Les Premières Leçons deMusique en Sol-Fa pour les Congolais by Alice D. Cobble, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Le Statut Juridique de la femme indigène au Congo Belge, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Costa Rica, 1947-59 (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Cuba
  - Biographical materials, 1947-56 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 1920-59 (Box 10, Folder 24-25)
  - General, 1924-72, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Czechoslovakia
  - Biographical materials, 1922-54 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - General, 1918-50, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Publications, 1944-63 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Dahomey (Benin): conference report, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Denmark
  - Biographical materials, 1921-80 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - General, 1921-63, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Dominican Republic
  - Biographical materials, 1945-68 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - General, 1946-48 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Publications, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Women's Organizations
    - Comision Interamericana de Mujeres, 1948-57 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Union Feminino Ibero-Americana (UFIA), 1947-49 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Ecuador
  - Biographical materials, 1943-68 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - General, 1864-1963 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Women's Organizations
    - Club Femenino de Cultura, 1945-64 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Union Nacional de Mujeres del Ecuador (UNME)
      - General, 1966-68, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Aqui Nosotras!, 1963-66 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Egypt
  - Biographical materials
    - General, 1949-75 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Shafik, Doria, 1949-57 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - General, 1863-1972, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Publications, 1934, 1954, undated (Box 11, Folder 20-21)
  - Women's organizations, 1955-66, undated (Box 11, Folder 22-23)
- Estonia, 1923-24 (Box 11, Folder 24)
- England
  - Biographical materials
    - Asquith, Margaret, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Bell, Gertrude, 1926-28 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1968-78 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - General, 1853-92 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Photograph: coal rationing, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Publications
    - General, 1920-58, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - The Englishwoman's Review of Social and Industrial Questions, 15 Apr 1901 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - "Sex, Race and Class" by Selma James, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Women and war, 1918-49 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Queens, 1950-51 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Women's organizations
    - General, 1948-68, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Fawcett Society, 1956-69 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - National Council of Women, 1963-67 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - National Union of Tradeswomen's Guilds, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Somerville Club, 1881 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - The Women's Council, 1963-69 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Women's Freedom League, 1932 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Women's Royal Voluntary Service Bulletin, 1967-69 (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Ethiopia
  - Biographical materials: Empress Menen, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Publications: Ethiopia Observer Apr 1957 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Women's Organizations
    - General, 1966, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Ethiopian Council of Social Welfare, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Ethiopian Women's Welfare Association, 1960-62, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - YWCA, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Fiji
  - Women's Organizations
    - Fiji Women's Club, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - South Pacific Commission Community Education Training Centre, 1966-67, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Women's Interests Office, 1960-66 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Finland
  - Biographical materials, 1952-64, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - General, 1913-70, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Publication: Sju Årtionden, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Women's Organizations
    - General, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Association 9, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - National Council of Women, 1951-54 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - National Federation of Business and Professional Women, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- France [see also Oversize materials]
  - Biographical materials
    - Bouglé, Marie-Louise, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Brunschvieg, Cécile Léon, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Casanova, Danielle, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - DeGaulle, Yvonne, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - de L'Euclos, Ninon, 1843 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - De Staël, Mme., 1816-1883 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Duchesne, Mother Rose Philippine, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Durand, Marguerite, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Giroud, Francoise, 1974-75 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Joan of Arc, 1926-31 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Lefaucheux, Madamee, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Michel, Louise, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Parturier, Françoise, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - General, 1919-75 (Box 14, Folder 14-15)
  - Congrès National des Droits Civils et du Suffrage des Femmes, 1908 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence describing German occupation by Alice Lachmund and Elizabeth Hoyt Beatty, 1940, 1942 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Exhibition, "Les Françaises a Ravensbrück," 1959 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Publications
    - Cahier de Recherches, "Femmes et Institutions littéraires," No. 13, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - femmes d'aujourd'hui, 7 Jun 1972 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Le Corps Lesbien by Monique Wittig, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - j'ai tué emma s. by Emma Santos, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - La Participation des femmes à la vie civique by Marie-Thérèse Renard, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Some Women of France, Parts 2 and 3by C.L. Fitch, 1920 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Sorcières, La Nourriture, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Témoignage d'une Infirmière by Lucile Sumpt, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Le Trait d'Union, Feb 1928 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Women in French history, 1898-1978 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Women of Paris by André Maurois, translated by Norman Denny, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Women's Organizations
    - General, 1952-58, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Conseil National des Femmes Française, 1931-69 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Fédération Anarchiste, 1947, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Ligue Française pour le Droits des Femmes, 1921-60, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Mouvement Mondial des Mères, 1955-61 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Union Feminine Civique et Sociale
      - General, 1955-61 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Dialoguer, 1968-69 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - La Femme dans la Vie Sociale, miscellaneous issues, 1957-68 [see Oversize] (Box 16)
- Gambia, 1959-64 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Germany [see separate boxes] (Box 17)
- Ghana
  - Biographical materials, 1960-63, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1956-72 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Conference: Federation of Ghana Women, 11 Aug 1960 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - "Fundamentals of Comparative Education" term paper by Dr. George Bereday, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - "Mass Education Women's Work Handbook," 1964 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Women's Organizations
    - General, 1957-69 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Ghana Women's Movement, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - YWCA of Ghana, 1966-67 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Great Britain [see England, Ireland, Scotland, Wales]
  - Greece
    - Clippings and articles, 1863-1979 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - General, 1926-63, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Publications, 1964-87, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Women's Organizations
      - General, 1956-68, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Hellenic National Graduate Nurses' Association, 1965-68 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - National Council of Greek Women, 1958-64 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Photo of Greek nurses; sample of embroidery (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Grenada, British West Indies, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Guatemala
    - Clippings, 1959-65, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - General, 1961-87, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Guyana
    - Conferences and reports
      - Conference of Women Trade Unionists, 1964, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - Conference of Women's Groups and Organisations on Sugar Estates, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - General, 1959, undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Women's organizations
      - General, 1960, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - Association of Workers in Home Economics, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 24)